<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rany Stephan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rany Stephan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/ranycs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My First Note</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/notes/my-first-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/notes/my-first-note/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first note.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a graduate student at Stanford University pursuing an M.S. in Mathematical and Computational Finance. I have a background in finance, computer science, and applied mathematics from the American University of Beirut. My research interests lie at the intersection of these fields, with a focus on applying quantitative and computational techniques to solve complex financial problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/ranycs/Resume.pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;800px&#34; style=&#34;border: none;&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-projects&#34;&gt;Research Projects&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;two-level-learning-augmented-caching-for-long-context-llm-inference&#34;&gt;Two-Level Learning-Augmented Caching for Long-Context LLM Inference&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2024&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Paper&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/ranycs/cs264project_research_final.pdf&#xA;&#34;&gt;Two-Level Learning-Augmented Caching for Long-Context LLM Inference: A Beyond Worst-Case Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors&lt;/strong&gt;: Rany Stephan (Stanford University)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: Large Language Models (LLMs) with extended context windows face a critical challenge: recent empirical studies show accuracy degradation in multi-turn conversations compared to single-turn settings, even within the model&amp;rsquo;s context limit. We formalize this long-chat degradation as a hierarchical online caching problem and introduce LATEM (Learning-Augmented Two-level Marking), a learning-augmented algorithm that manages both message-level and token-level caches. We prove that LATEM achieves consistency ratio 2 + O(η/OPT) when predictions have error η, and O(log km + log k′t/ε)-robustness in the worst case, where km is the message cache size, k′t = ⌊kt/km⌋ is the effective token cache per message, and ε is the trust parameter. Our analysis extends the learning-augmented framework to hierarchical caches with interdependent eviction decisions, offering, to our knowledge, the first formal consistency–robustness guarantees for hierarchical KV-cache management in LLMs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects--competitions&#34;&gt;Projects &amp;amp; Competitions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;teaching-assistant-stanford-mlab-acm-machine-learning-lab&#34;&gt;Teaching Assistant, Stanford MLab (ACM Machine Learning Lab)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oct 2025 - Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications&#34;&gt;Publications&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;opportunities-for-circular-economy-in-waste-reuse-insights-from-social-media-data-mining&#34;&gt;Opportunities for circular economy in waste reuse: Insights from social media data mining&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Journal of Resources, Conservation and Recycling&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citation:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Badran, S., Massoud, M.A., Stephan, R., Elbassuonı, S., Chalak, A., &amp;amp; Abıad, M.G. (2025). Opportunities for circular economy in waste reuse: Insights from social media data mining. &lt;em&gt;Resources, Conservation and Recycling&lt;/em&gt;, 215, 108100. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.resconrec.2024.108100&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.resconrec.2024.108100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Transitioning to circular economy requires robust waste management to minimize waste, maximize resource use, and promote recycling and reuse. This study examines reuse as a primary waste prevention strategy within this framework. It identifies commonly reused items and assesses the environmental benefits of online second-hand shops versus disposal or purchasing new items. AI methodologies, including information retrieval and machine learning, analyzed over 1000 images from Lebanese Instagram thrift shops to train a classifier. Environmental impacts were quantified using LCA studies. Results show textiles, clothing, and shoes are the most reused items. Online thrift shops offer affordable, sustainable clothing, reducing the need for new production. Most reused items were in good condition, indicating they can replace new ones, conserving resources. Reuse outperforms recycling, though furniture and electronics have lower reuse rates. AI&amp;rsquo;s potential in waste management and the importance of sustainable reuse practices are highlighted, suggesting significant efficiency and cost improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/ranycs/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-experience&#34;&gt;Research Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;graduate-researcher-convex-optimization-for-portfolio-transition&#34;&gt;Graduate Researcher, Convex Optimization for Portfolio Transition&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advisor: Prof. Stephen Boyd (June 2025 - Present)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Develop portfolio transition strategies using &lt;strong&gt;Model Predictive Control (MPC)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;convex optimization&lt;/strong&gt; to minimize implementation shortfall while tracking a benchmark. &lt;strong&gt;Manuscript in progress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Engineer a high-fidelity backtesting framework in &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; using &lt;strong&gt;CVXPY&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Pandas&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;NumPy&lt;/strong&gt; to simulate multi-period portfolio transitions under transaction costs and market impact models.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Implement efficient numerical methods, including sparse Cholesky factorization and risk factor models to accelerate optimization solver performance within the simulation environment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;graduate-researcher-fixed-income-modeling&#34;&gt;Graduate Researcher, Fixed Income Modeling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advisor: Prof. Darrell Duffie (Dec 2024 - Present)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
